# **DAVE JODHAN**

(718)-885-6573 davejodhan@hotmail.com https://github.com/daveswork

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Highly talented technical project leader with over 10 years experience working on business class real-time voice and data networks. Responsibilities include working with the software development teams to scale or troubleshoot underlying infrastructure, coordinating replacement/repairs with contractors, automating maintenance reports for internal operations teams, as well as generating usage statistics for upper management.

#### **CORE QUALIFICATIONS**

- Producing technical documentation for both end users as well as Engineering teams (samples available upon request).
- Experience working within both Organic and Mechanistic organisations.
- US Army NCO, with experience training and leading soldiers in maintenance operations for Army Air Traffic Control Systems.
- Bachelor's degree (cum laude) in Technical Management.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Infrastructure and Ops Engineer

# Independent Contractor (Brandoor Group, Merchants NYC)

April 2017- Present

- Provided technical support for both AWS and physical servers running CentOS, Ubuntu and AMI.
- Managed cloud infrastructure with Ansible and Puppet.

# Network Engineer Intersection

Feb 2016 - April 2017

- Leveraged RESTful APIs available on various platforms to deploy over 300+ routers and WAPs for the LinkNYC project, one of the largest urban Wi-Fi Network.
- Automated WiFi Usage reports for consumption by the sales and marketing team as well as capacity and health reports for engineering and support team.
- Work with the Fiber deployment team to resolve Layer 1 issues on a DWDM network.
- Evaluate candidates hardware for new deployments, such as Extreme, Huawei, MiroTek, etc.
- Managed local DNS services for over 600 nodes using BIND, as well supported the DHCP infrastructure.
- Managed a heterogeneous network environment consisting of Cisco, Juniper and Ruckus hardware.
- Turned up VPNs as needed to connect local Development environment to AWS VPCs.
- Planned and executed OS upgrades within NYC DoITT approved maintenance windows.
- Worked with hardware vendor engineering teams to capture relevant diagnostic data to aid in the production of bug fixes.

NOC Engineer OnSIP Jul 2011 – Nov 2015

- Implemented the network infrastructure for both dev and production environments to migrate OnSIP's platform from a monolithic design to a geographically distributed SOA.
- Captured metrics for capacity planning for both bandwidth and phone number inventory.
- Provided technical documentation for LAN & WAN infrastructure as well as instructions for configuring PBXs for use with OnSIP's hosted trunking product.
- Created Python and Bash scripts to automate testing and generate usage reports.
- Provisioned IPv6 connectivity to the development stack to mimic production environment

- Deployed and managed Juniper's Dynamic VPN services to the New Jersey office , in support of Accounting and Finance activities
- Provided technical assistance in testing and turnup of IPSec tunnels to Verizon's voice network using Cisco devices, and assisted in migration of the same configuration to Linux Gateways (using OpenSwan)
- Produced and tested configuration instructions for 5 PBX's in support of the OnSIP Hosted Trunking product
- Generate carrier utilization reports and use tools such as Python for parsing carrier reports and collecting useful data
- Performing interop testing as part of the new service provider turn up process and submit test results in the requested format.

## **IT Support Specialist**

#### **Bronx VA Medical Center**

Jan 2009 - Jan2011

- Developed VBA macros to automate logging of common tickets.
- Created user accounts for new hires and updated permissions for access to required subsystems.

# **E**DUCATION

AWS Solutions Architect Associate certification	2017
Juniper JNCIA	2013
Cisco CCNA	2010
Bachelor's degree in Technical Management	2008

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

## **Projects**

- WAP Activation and Update tool. Using Python, created CLI based tool which takes two arguments, the MAC address of a WAP and the ten character site-id of a Link kiosk and updates the WLAN controller for the WAP using data from an external resource.
- **Network Hardware Report Automation**. Using SolarWind's native SWQL, automated the daily reporting of network hardware status, which included "parent-child" logic, to exclude downstream hardware if an upstream device has failed (making the downstream equipment unreachable).
- **VoIP Load tester**. Using a combination of Asterisk running on Ubuntu 16, as well as Python scripts generate test calls across the network and utilized tshark to generate call quality reports from pcaps.
- **VoIP rate comparison tool**. Using VBA, created macros which compared VoIP rates from various wholesale providers. Some of the logic designed included interstate and intrastate rates and short-call surcharges.

## **Languages and Technologies**

- Python, Flask, Django, ES6 (JavaScript), React HTML/CSS, VBA, SQL, Git/GitHub, SIP/HTTP, TCP/UDP, IP
- CentOS 6/7, Ubuntu 14 & 16, AWS EC2/S3/IAM, SolarWinds, Nagios, Cacti, Ansible.
- BGP, OSPF, IPv4, IPv6, IPSec VPNs, GREs, SNMP
- Cisco ISR 890 and 2900 routers, ASA 5505, Catalyst 2960 switches
- Juniper MX-80, QFX 5100, ACX-2200, ACX-1100, SRX100, SRX210, J-2320, EX-4300
- Ruckus SCG-200, R410s